Manjunath G M



Personal Details

Date of Birth: 14th March 1980

Nationality: Indian

Current Location: Bangalore

Contact

Address:

No 41-42, Flat No. 303, 2nd Floor, 3rd Main, 1st Cross, RBI Layout, JP Nagar 7th phase, Near BBMP Office, Bengaluru-560078, Karnataka, India

Phone:

+91 (0)98 454 67389

Email:

manjunathagm@gmail.com

Summary

18 years of experience having sound software development skills. Most significant software development skills include high proficiency in creating applications using PHP, Python, Java and JavaScript for a wide variety of environments, including the server, the web (server-side and client-side) and mobile devices. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects.

Professional Skills

Programming
Languages

PHP with OOPS., Java, SmartFoxServer
2x Server Extension and Python.

Web / Application
Servers

Apache, Nginx, SmartFoxServer 2x, Node
JS

Relational/NoSQL
Databases

Web Services

PHP with OOPS., Java, SmartFoxServer
2x Server Extension and Python.

Apache, Nginx, SmartFoxServer 2x, Node
JS

MySQL, MongoDB and AWS DynamoDB

SOAP, REST, AJAX and Web Sockets

PHP Frameworks Laravel and Codeigniter

Front End Standards HTML 5, HTML 4, XHTML, CSS, including CSS3, DOM, JavaScript, JavaScript libraries jQuery, React JS and JS Framework

AngularJS

Cloud Computing **AWS:- CDN**, **S3**, **EC2**, **EBS**, **RDS** for MySQL, Elastic IP, **ELB**/HAProxy LB, **Auto**

Scaling, Amplify, Route53, CloudWatch

and Microsoft Azure services.

Operating Systems Unix/Linux Ubuntu,

Windows95/98/2000/XP/2003/Vista/Windo

ws7/Windows8,Mac

Other Programming C, bash/shell script

Google APIs Maps API, Analytics API, Graph/Charts

API

Twitch/Mixer APIs Twitch Video Extension, Mixplay and

Mixer chat APIs

APIs Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and Youtube

Payment Gateways PayPal, CCAvenue, Razorpay, API Authorize.net and Stripe

Tools & Utilities IDEs: Visual Studio Code, PhpStorm,

Eclipse, NetBeans, IntelliJ IDEA.

Source Code Control: Subversion, Git

Code/Distribution Management: Ant, Capistrano, Hudson/Jenkins, JIRA and

Bugzilla

Monitoring Tool: Nagios and Munin

Strengths

- Self-motivated, decisive, strongwilled and goal-oriented.
- Able to work as a good Team Member in a fast-paced team environment as well as focus on individual projects with set deadlines.
- Effective Problem-solver and Quick Learner.
- Eager to learn new technologies and skills.

Project Links

https://digitalacademy360.com/

https://www.acaders.com/

https://www.vrotors.com/

https://www.skybound.com/

https://store.skybound.com/

http://www.realmadridkidsplanet.com/

https://www.kidsindustries.com/aquafresh

toolkit

https://www.brontetennis.com/?index

https://collingwoodcurlingclub.ca/

https://www.creemoresprings.com/en/ind

ex

http://ecologicmontana.com/

http://www.fugocreative.com/oms/login.p

hp

http://www.suvidhajobs.in/

Languages

- English
- Kannada
- Hindi

Hobbies

- Travelling
- Cycling
- Swimming
- Reading blogs

Experience

Head of Full Stack - 05/2022 to Present **IAT Technologies Pvt. Ltd.**, Bangalore

- Converted designs to code for digitalacademy360.com & acaders.com.
- Responsible for website development & maintenance.
- Handling Dev, Stage and Production push. Setting up dev, stage and production servers on Amazon EC2 servers.
- Technologies worked on: HTML, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap5, JavaScript, jQuery, React JS, Next JS.

Consultant - 12/2016 to 05/2022 VRotors Inc., California (Working from Bangalore, India)

Project Lead - 06/2015 to 12/2015
Snowtint Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore

Senior Software Engineer - 08/2014 to 05/2015 Pescados Software India Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore

Software Engineer - 05/2014 to 08/2014 **Probe Equity Research Pvt. Ltd.**, Bangalore

Systems Engineer - 10/2013 to 04/2014 I2Play Interactive Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore

Freelancer - 08/2012 to 10/2013 VSM Global Services, Bangalore

Technical Lead - 08/2010 to 07/2012

Digital Chocolate IT & Gaming Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore

Senior Software Engineer - 03/2010 to 08/2010 Software Engineer - 07/2007 to 05/2008 TLI Software Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore

Project Lead - 05/2008 to 03/2010 **SPA Computers Pvt. Ltd.**, Bangalore (Company Closed).

Software Engineer - 03/2007 to 07/2007 **Nagaraj Technologies Pvt. Ltd.**, Bangalore

Software Developer - 03/2006 to 03/2007 **OpenSols InfoTech Pvt. Ltd.**, Bangalore (Company Closed).

Web Developer - 07/2005 to 05/2006 Enspire Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore (Company Closed).

Education

Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science & Engineering – 2004, Visveswaraiah Technological University, Karnataka, India